（至今走过的路）
嘿 迪恩 是我
Hey, Dean. It's me.
你回来多久了 萨姆
How long you been back, Sam?
一年了
About a year.
这一整年你一直都在
You been back practically this whole time?!
你终于美梦成真 你渴望一个家
You finally had what you wanted. You wanted a family.
我要你去 你是个猎魔人
I need you to go. You're a hunter.
是萨姆 他变了
It's Sam. He's different.
是他的灵魂 不见了
It's his soul. It's gone.
你们抓个活生生的始祖给我
You bag me a live Alpha,
我就把你家小萨姆的灵魂还给他
and I'll give you little Sammy's soul back.
我们会等待一个命令
We're waiting for the word.
他们的始祖正在组建一支军队
Their alpha's building an army.
似乎我们就要开战了
Like we're going to war.
给我抓超自然生物来
Bring me creatures.
如果你是始祖的话 那谁造就了你呢
But if you're the first… Who made you?
万物皆有源
We all have our mothers.
我们这些魔怪死了之后 魂归何处呢
When we freaks die, where do we go?
天堂上不去 地狱亦无门
Not heaven, not hell.
- 炼狱 - 我要占领它
- Purgatory. - And I want it.
- 我想拿回我的灵魂 - 我办不到
- I want my soul back. - I can't.
萨姆的灵魂一直被封印在牢笼里
Sam's soul has been locked in the cage.
和米迦勒还有路西法一起
with Michael and Lucifer.
灵魂回到我体内会让我彻底崩溃
Putting this thing back in would smash me to bits.
根本无法预料会发生什么
We have no idea what will happen.
麻痹瘫痪 精神错乱 精神性疼痛
Paralysis, insanity, psychic pain,
巨大的痛苦会让他一辈子不得安宁
so profound that he's locked inside himself for the rest of his life.
死亡骑士
The horseman of Death,
又见面了 迪恩
Hello, Dean.
- 死亡骑士说他能建一个屏障 - 一个屏障
- Death said he can put up a wall. - A wall?
地狱的一切你都会忘记
You wouldn't remember hell.
赌注是什么
What's the bet?
我想让你替我工作一天
I want you to be me for one day.
那是我的人生 我的灵魂 我不想要了
It's my life. It's my soul. I don't want it.
你需要用血孽玷污你的皮囊
You need to scar your vessel.
抱歉了
Sorry.
别这么做
Don't do this.
别去碰那个屏障
Don't scratch the wall.
（如今）
你还好吗
How you doing?
很好 好极了
I'm great. This is great.
佩妮 没事的
Penny, it's gonna be okay.
知道吗 洗澡时挂掉的人比坠机的多了去了
You know, a lot more people die in the shower.
太欣慰了 谢谢
Good to know. Thanks.
我真没想到我们会遇到这种鬼天气
I didn't think we'd run into any weather, though.
能不能先着落 求你了
Look, can we just land? Please?
再坚持几分钟好吗 很近了
Couple minutes. All right? We're close.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
- 那是什么 - 啥
- What was that?! - What?
刚刚有东西从窗前掠过 而且很大只
Something just flew by the window! It was huge!
可能就是只鸟罢了
Probably just a bird, okay?
不不不 斯坦 那绝不是鸟
No! No, Stan, that was not a bird.
不然是啥
Well, then, what was it?
我不知道
I don't know.
佩妮 外面啥都没有
Penny, there's nothing out there.
我保证
I promise.
你闭上眼放松下 好吗
Hey, just close your eyes, okay?
没事的 靠到椅背上
It's okay. Just lean back.
放松点儿
Try to relax.
想一些迷人的地方
Think of someplace nice.
海浪轻抚沙滩
Waves on a beach.
斯坦
Stan?!
我的天啊
Ohh! Oh, my god!
不 不 不要啊
No, no, no, no, no, no!
[邪恶力量 第6季第12集]
怎么样
Well?
他的灵魂归位了
His soul is in place.
那他还能醒过来么
Is he ever gonna wake up?
我又不是人类医生 迪恩
I'm not a human doctor, Dean.
你就不能瞎猜下吗
Could you take a guess?
好吧
Okay.
很可能醒不来
Probably not.
- 你还能再直接点儿 - 抱歉 迪恩
- Oh, well, don't sugarcoat it. - I'm sorry, Dean,
但我警告过你别把那灵魂塞回萨姆体内
But I warned you not to put that thing back inside him.
那我该怎么做
What was I supposed to do?
让T-1000（《终结者2》中的机械杀手）到处乱逛 祈祷他千万别开火吗
Let T-1000 walk around, hope he doesn't open fire?
那我跟你说说我触摸他灵魂时的感觉吧
Let me tell you what his soul felt like when I touched it.
就像是被活剥了一样 迪恩
Like it had been skinned alive, Dean.
如果你想你弟弟死 就该给他个痛快
If you wanted to kill your brother, you should have done it outright.
我老爸总说
Like my daddy always said,
酒虽伤肝但却疗心
"Just 'cause it kills your liver don't mean it ain't medicine."
萨姆还在睡吗
Sam still asleep?
是的
Yeah.
他会醒的
He'll wake up.
是啊
Yeah.
迪恩 他经历过多少大风大浪啊
Dean, he's been through how much?
可他总是能挺过来
Somehow, he always bounces back.
但他从没经历过这个
He's never been through this.
- 有活儿了 - 八成是
- Job? - Might be.
我来帮你吧
Can I help?
让我去图书馆什么的
Send me to the library? Anything?
夫妻俩驾驶轻型飞机
Couple goes up in a light plane.
刚刚在树林里找到飞机残骸
Wreckage was just found in the woods.
一对儿巴迪·豪利（摇滚歌手 因飞机坠毁身亡）嘛
Couple of Buddy Hollys?
看起来没什么可疑的呀
Doesn't really seem like "News of the weird."
飞行员在17英里外被发现 全身烧焦
Pilot was found 17 miles away, flambed.
女孩不见了
Girl's just gone.
没尸体 什么都没有
No body, no nothing.
嗯 我听着呢
Okay, I'm not changing the channel.
迪恩
Dean.
萨姆
Sam?
你…
Are you …
见到你真好
Good to see you.
等等
Wait.
我看到你…
I saw you …
我感受到路西法扭断了你的脖子
I-I felt Lucifer snap your neck.
那个 小卡那时…
Well, Cass kind of …
小卡还活着吗
Cass is alive?
是 小卡他没事 萨姆 你还好吗
Yeah, Cass … Cass is fine. Sam, are you okay?
其实吧 呃…
Actually, um…
我快饿瘪了
I'm starving.
那个 萨姆
So, Sam…
嗯
Yeah?
你最后的记忆是什么
…What's the last thing you remember?
那片旷野 之后我就掉下去了
The field. And then I fell.
好吧 再之后呢
Okay. And then?
我在安全屋里醒过来
I woke up in the panic room.
就这样吗
That's it?
你真的不记得…
You really don't remember …
咱就谢天谢地吧
Let's be glad.
谁想记得那些破事儿啊
Who wants to remember all that hell?
那个 我消失了多久
Well, h-how long was I gone?
- 大概一年半吧 - 什么
- About a year and a half. - What?
我在下面
I was downstairs…
我什么都不记得了
I don't remember anything.
那么 我怎么回来的 是小卡吗
S-so, how'd I get back? Was it Cass?
不全是
Not exactly.
迪恩 你干了什么
Dean, what did you do?
我和死亡…
Me and Death …
死亡 死亡骑士吗
Death?! The horseman?
我有我的手段
I had leverage.
已经完事儿了
It's done.
- 你确定吗 - 都结束了
- You sure? - It's over.
一切都一笔勾销
Slate's wiped.
是啊 真是干净又利落啊
Well, isn't this just neat and clean?
没错 这次就是
Yes, it is … for once.
还有什么要告诉我的吗
Is there anything else I should know?
没了
No.
还要啤酒吗
Another beer?
好啊
Uh, yeah.
喂
Hey.
他还好吗
How is he?
他…
He's, uh…
不错 很不错 比我期望的好多了
He's good. Really good. Better than I could have hoped.
咋了 干嘛一副苦逼脸
What? Why the poopface?
他有所好转我很高兴 真的
I'm glad he's better. I really am.
但是
But…
那孩子几天前还把刀架我脖子上 准备弑父
That kid went straight-up menendez on me not 10 days ago.
现在一切就这么过去了
And now it's all just… Erased?
抱歉 我现在看他就浑身不自在
Sorry. I'm having a bit of a hard time even looking at him.
当时那不是萨姆
It wasn't Sam.
好吧 或许那并不全是萨姆的本意
Well, maybe it wasn't all Sam,
但确实是他 迪恩
but it was him, Dean.
是 那你想怎样 鲍比 告诉他一切吗
Well, what do you want to do, Bobby? We tell him everything?
不 我倒想告诉他呢
No. Just wish I could, that's all.
如果咱把那些破事儿都告诉他
Yeah, but if we start throwing that crap at him,
天知道会怎样
We don't know what's gonna happen.
- 说不定 说不定会打破屏障 - 我知道
- It could … it could crack the wall. - I know. I know.
所以呢
So, you know what?
在我看来 这是个白来的恩赐
As far as I'm concerned, it's a gift horse,
做人要知足
and I'm not looking for teeth.
我还要对死亡骑士感恩戴德呢
I'm sending Death a damn fruit basket.
他早晚会知道
He's gonna find out, you know.
不管怎样
One way or another,
有人会告诉他 或者他自己会想明白
someone will tell him, or he'll figure it out on his own.
他不是傻子
He's not dumb.
应该由我们告诉他
He should hear it from us.
咱先把这事儿放一放 行吗
Can we just leave it alone for the moment, please?
好
Okay.
但你最好做好最坏的打算
But you better prep for the "B" Side,
因为如果萨姆发现咱们糊弄他
'cause when Sam realizes we're shining him…
事情就不好看了
It ain't gonna be cute.
萨姆还在睡吗
Sam still asleep?
嗯 让他歇歇吧 待会儿再打给他
Yeah, let him rest. We'll call him later.
从哪儿打给我
Call me from where?
俄勒冈有个案子
Uh, there's this thing in Oregon.
- 太好了 我也去 - 别介
- Great. I'm in. - Whoa, whoa.
你刚「活」过来
You just got vertical.
是啊 我醒了 感觉良好
Exactly. I'm up. I'm good.
先窝家看几天狗血剧也没啥不好
Well, a few more days of crap cable couldn't hurt.
才怪 当初你从地狱回来时是这样吗
Right. Because that's what you did when you got back from hell.
好吧
All right.
你 我和鲍比
You, me, and Bobby.
你们去吧 有你俩就行了
Oh, you two go on ahead. You got this covered.
我 我忘了我答应了那个白痴鲁弗斯
I, uh, forgot I promised that idjit Rufus.
要帮他接电话 所以…
I'd work the phones for him, so…
确定吗
You sure?
是 确定
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你俩好好叙叙 好吧
You two enjoy catching up, okay?
他怎么回事啊
What was that?
更年期 还喝高了
One part age, three parts liquor.
好的警官 谢谢你
Uh, you got it, officer. Thank you.
你也是
You too.
听好了 除了飞机失事
So, get this … besides the crash,
这周镇上还发生了两起失踪案
there were two other disappearances in town this week.
- 真的吗 - 对 上周末
- Really? - Yeah, last weekend,
一个女大学生在她公寓里消失了
a college girl vanished from her apartment.
在十七楼
On the 17th floor.
还有 三天前
Then, three days ago,
有个女生放学后就再也没回家
another girl didn't make it home from school.
- 这两人认识吗 - 不认识 没有联系
- They know each other? - No. No connection.
都是年轻女性 和飞机失事中的女孩一样
Just young and female, like the plane-crash girl.
啥会让一个女孩从半空中消失啊
What would disappear a girl out of the sky, anyway?
问得好
Good question.
- 你从未尝试过吗 - 尝试什么
- So you never even tried, huh? - Tried?
尝试好好过日子 那件事之后
To go live a life…after.
你承诺过的 记得吧
You do remember you promised that, right?
是的 我记得
Yeah, I remember.
那你为什么不试一下
So, why didn't you try?
你怎么知道我没有
What makes you think I didn't?
看看你 看看这个
'cause look at you. Look at this.
你和以前一模一样
You're exactly the same.
可能是吧
Yeah, you're probably right.
莉莎和本与我共同生活了一年
I was with them for a year … Lisa and Ben.
一年
A year?
后来呢
So then what?
还是不尽人意
Didn't work out.
（波特兰）
你是佩妮·迪瑟婷的妹妹吧
You're, uh…Penny Dessertine's sister, right?
我们想问你几个问题
Uh, we'd just like to ask you a few questions.
之前已经有警察来过了 我很累
Look, the cops already came by. I'm tired.
如果你们不介意的话
So, if you don't mind …
我理解 真的
I-I understand. Really, I do.
我知道这非常痛苦
I know how hard this must be.
我们只是想弄清楚事情的原委
We'd just like to figure out what happened.
用不了多久 我保证
This will be quick. I promise.
好吧 进来
Okay. Fine. Come in.
佩妮本人很害羞
Penny was very shy. To herself.
她一点都不喜欢冒险
Not at all what you'd call adventurous.
那干嘛雷雨天气还坐双座飞机出游
What, like flying through a lightning storm in a two-seater?
她其实很害怕
She was terrified of that thing.
她这么做是为了斯坦
She just did it for Stan.
斯坦
Stan?
他们刚开始认真交往
They were just starting to get serious.
她不想让他觉得 她没兴趣
She didn't want to seem, you know…not interested.
我多希望我让她呆在家里
I just wish I'd told her to stay home.
我们连她的遗体都找不到
We don't even have a body to bury.
你有何发现
Hey. What do you got?
看起来那两个失踪的女孩
Well, looks like those other two missing girls.
都为上帝烤过饼干
both baked cookies for the lord.
- 啥 密码吗 - 不是
- What is that? Code? - No.
教堂唱诗班 糕饼义卖 贞洁戒指社团
Church choir, bake sales, promise-ring clubs …
这类活动
the works.
她们都是好女孩
They were good girls.
但佩妮都不是基督教徒…
But Penny wasn't even a christian, so …
我另有想法
I have another theory.
佩妮的日记
Penny's diary.
你从她房间里偷的吗
Did you steal that from her room?
我真高兴你这么问我
I love that you even asked me that.
- 我干嘛不问 - 没理由
- And why wouldn't I? - No reason.
女孩绑架案 如果和宗教无关
So, girl-nappings … what if it's not about religion?
而是关于贞洁呢
What if it's about purity?
你是说 她们都是
You mean you think they're all …
处女 萨姆 都是处女
Virgins, Sam. Virgins.
佩妮可二十二岁了
Penny was 22.
- 住粉红色的房间 - 那又怎样
- Yeah, with a pink room. - So?
还有泰迪熊
And stuffed teddy bears.
好吧 但是你真的认为…
Fine. But you really think …
「我决定把我最珍贵的东西献给斯坦」
"I've decided I'm going to give Stan my most precious gift."
从你嘴里说出来真是毛骨悚然
Wow. That sounded really creepy coming out of your mouth.
我语气多生动啊
I think I delivered it.
你知道 你可以从日记着手
You know, you … you could have led with the diary. You know?
不管怎样 就算你说的对
Anyways, let's say you're right. Fine.
谁会要处女呢
Who would want virgins?
我怎么知道
You got me.
我喜欢有经验的女人
I prefer ladies with experience.
不
No.
一切发生得太快了
It happened so fast.
梅利莎 没事的
It's all right, Melissa.
袭击你的是什么东西
What came at you?
你可以告诉我们
You can tell us.
看起来好像是
It … it looked like a…
一只很大的蝙蝠
…a giant bat.
你认为我在编故事 对吧
You think I'm making it up, right?
那个男人也这么说
That's what the other man said.
我不一样
Well, I'm not the other man.
它径直就冲我来了
It came right at me.
我发誓 是庞然大物
It was huge. I swear.
所以我受伤了
That's how I got this.
它攻击了你
So, it attacked.
然后发生了什么事
And then what happened?
我不知道了
I don't know.
我昏倒了 当我醒来后 它不见了
I passed out, and when I woke up, it was gone.
你还能想起其他什么事情不
Is there anything else you can think of?
任何事情
Anything you can tell us,
即使是无关紧要的事
even if it doesn't seem important?
我的戒指丢了
Well, my ring got lost.
要不就是那东西偷走了 如果说得通的话
Or else that thing stole it, if that makes any sense.
- 什么样的戒指 - 金的
- What kind of ring? - Gold.
贞洁戒指
Promise ring.
是从 教堂得来的吗
So, uh… From, like, a church?
代表纯洁的戒指
Like … like a purity ring?
是的 怎么了
Yeah. Why?
我想要问一句
I got to ask.
梅利莎
Uh, Melissa…
不是要对你做什么评判
Look, nobody is, uh, judging anybody here, okay?
相信我 但是
Believe me. But…
你真的配得上那戒指吗
Should you really be wearing that ring?
- 我 我是 - 真的
- Well, I-I mean, I-I am … - Really?
马特·贝尼那次不算
Matt Barne didn't count.
你认为蝙蝠侠想要强奸她吗
So, what, you think batman tried to rape her?
他确实有很大火气
Well, he does carry a lot of rage.
但是他因为她不是处而拒绝了她
But he rejected her because she was already dehymenated, huh?
是吗
You think?
我想这说明
I think it just goes to show.
开放点儿完全没坏处啊
that being easy's pretty much all upside.
那么 什么东西喜欢处女和金子
So, what kind of thing likes virgins and gold?
吹牛老爹（歌手）
P. Diddy?
- 这感觉真好 - 什么感觉
- You know, it's comforting. - What's that?
我死了一年 复活
I died for a year, came back,
而你依然那么的冷
and you're still not funny.
闭嘴 我很风趣的
Shut up. I'm hilarious.
这不可能
This can't be possible.
说来听听
Try me.
我谷歌了火焰 爪子 飞行
Um, I googled "Fire, " "Claws, " "Flying, "
绑架处女 还有金子
"Stealing virgins, " And "Gold, "
每次的查询结果都是一个
And it all takes me to the same place.
什么
Where?
魔兽世界玩家网站
"World of warcraft" Fansites.
我不知道这啥意思
I don't know what that means.
龙 老兄
Dragons, dude.
看吧 早说过 不可能
See? Told you. Not possible.
其实 很可能就是
Actually, it might be.
怎么可能 哪儿可能啊
How? In what reality?
这年头无奇不有
It's been a strange year.
我们应该听听其他人的意见
We should get a second opinion.
你了解龙吗
What do you know about dragons?
什么 不了解
What? Nothing.
说真的
Seriously.
这又不是尼斯湖水怪 迪恩
Well, they're not like the loch ness monster, Dean.
龙不存在
Dragons aren't real.
你能打几个电话询问下吗
Could you make a few calls?
给谁 霍格沃兹吗
To who? Hogwarts?
试试无妨
Humor me.
好吧
Fine.
你真是个有学问的绅士
You're a gentleman and a scholar.
咱们那失忆的小孩儿怎么样了
Hey, how's "Memento" doing over there?
识破你的什么谎言了吗
He caught you in any lies yet?
一切安好 萨姆向你问好
Everything's fine. Sam says hey.
你还好吗
You okay?
很好
Yeah.
鲍比说什么了没
Bobby say anything?
没有
Nope.
老爸没写过任何关于龙的事
Dad never wrote anything about dragons.
我保证
I promise.
如果我在里面读到过《大魔域》（80年代奇幻小说） 我会记得
I'd remember if I read "The neverending story" in there.
咱们最近狩猎过剥皮行者吗
Hey, did we hunt a skinwalker lately?
没印象 怎么了
Doesn't ring a bell. Why?
只是 有些模糊的印象
I don't know. Just…Dejavu or something.
- 你确定吗 我发誓 - 别忘了
- Are you sure? I could have sworn… - You got to remember.
你的小脑壳里还有些凌乱
your eggs are still a little scrambled, right?
但是我很确定
But, yeah, I'm sure.
好吧
All right.
当我没说
Yeah. Never mind.
鲍比 查到了什么
Hey, Bobby. What do you got?
我居然没想起她来
Can't believe she didn't jump right to mind.
维斯艾克博士
Dr. Visyak.
中古研究系 西蒙菲莎大学
Medieval studies, S.F.U.
维斯艾克博士 西蒙菲莎大学
Dr. Visyak, S.F.U.
了解 谢了
Got it. Thanks.
我要去旧金山
All right. I'm going to San Francisco,
找到杀这玩意儿的方法
figure out how to kill these things.
你来找到它们的藏身地
You figure out where they are.
等下 鲍比有说他们爱在哪歇脚吗
W-wait. D-did Bobby say where they like to park?
没有
No.
不错 又得靠文献了
Great. Back to the lore.
怎么说 它们住在中土吗
Which says what? That they live in middle-earth?
不是 山洞
No. Caves.
真是个书呆子
You're such a nerd.
求你
Please.
放我走吧
Please let me go!
闭嘴
Shut up!
求你了
Please!
不要
No!
闭嘴
Shut up!
闭嘴 不然我把另一条也折了
Shut up, or I'll break the other one.
进去 快点
Now, get in there. Come on.
没事的 一切都会好的
It's okay. It's gonna be okay.
你好
Yes?
维斯艾克博士 我是迪恩·温彻斯特
Dr. Visyak. My name is Dean Winchester.
办公时间是周一和周五
Office hours are Monday and Friday.
鲍比·辛格让我来的
Bobby Singer sent me.
有人吗
Hello?
你好
Hi.
鲍比·辛格
Bobby Singer.
你下次见他的时候帮我带句话
Tell him something for me next time you see him.
嗯
Hmm?
直接踢他的蛋蛋就行了
Actually, just kick him in the jewels.
这样更诗意点儿
That's more poetic.
你俩关系还真不太好哈
No love lost between you two, huh?
不 正好相反
No. Just the opposite.
是吗
Oh?
让他来告诉你吧
That's his story to tell.
他个傻瓜
He's the idiot.
你这次为何而来
So, what's this about?
呃
Well.
是龙
Uh…Dragons.
真的假的
Really?
咋啦 不来个龙与地下城的玩笑么
What, no 12-sided-dice joke?
反正龙消失了 我们可以开开它们的玩笑
We can joke about them because they've disappeared.
但它们可不好玩
But they aren't funny.
一点也不
At all.
刚有一条空降到美国了
Well, one just flew in stateside.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
和传说丝毫不差
Fits the lore to a "T."
怎么会 为什么啊
But how? I mean, why?
都700年了
It's been 700 years.
博士 现如今满世界都是怪异现象
Banner crop of crazy all the way around these days, doc.
- 你想知道如何屠龙 - 是的
- So you want to know how to kill it. - That's right.
你得有把剑
Well, you need a blade.
呃
Uh…
好的 什么类型的
Okay. What kind of blade?
一把用龙血锻造的剑
One forged with dragon's blood.
就是说 杀死一条龙得要一把剑
So you need one to kill one,
但是锻造这把剑得杀死一条龙
but you got to kill one to make one.
这怎么行得通
How does that work out?
现今没多少屠龙剑了
Well, there aren't many dragon swords around anymore.
全世界最多也就五六把
Five or six, tops, worldwide.
是有把圣乔治之剑
I mean, there's the sword of St. George,
当然还有亚瑟王的湖中剑
And, of course, there's excalibur.
- 还有 - 你知道的可真多
- And there's - You know a lot about this stuff, don't you?
绝对的
Well, I sure as hell better.
我的地下室就有一把
I have one in the basement.
你有一把
You have one.
找它用了20年 数不清的时间
Finding it took two decades, countless hours,
还有和一位东欧大使的几场差劲的性爱
and some really bad sex with an eastern european ambassador,
但是我得到了
but, yeah.
不是真的吧
That is not real.
是真的吗
Is that real?
那是亚瑟王之剑吗
Is it excalibur?
不是
No.
这是布朗维克之剑（捷克传说中的杀人魔剑）
This…is the sword of Bruncvik.
我一生挚爱
Love of my life.
那这个水泥是怎么回事
So, uh, what's with the cement shoe?
那个时候流行把剑插到石头里
You know, binding sword to stone used to be all the rage.
这样可以保护剑
To protect them.
好吧 我们怎样才能把这个小可爱拔出来
All right, well, how do we get this puppy out?
得了 你懂的
Well, come on. You know this one.
得有一个勇敢的骑士
We need a brave knight.
愿意挺身而出去屠龙
who's willing to step up and kill the beast.
是啊
Right.
好吧 我
All right, well, I'll, uh…
我来试一试
Give it a whirl.
- 你不介意吧 - 请
- Do you mind? - Oh.
你还好吧
You okay?
好极啦
Never better.
天杀的 这也太牢固了吧
Oh, son of a bitch! That's really on there!
恐怕是这样的
Yeah, afraid so.
- 我还有个主意 - 什么
- Well, I have another idea. - What?
你不会喜欢的
Well, you're not gonna like it.
萨姆 迪恩在哪
Sam. Where's Dean?
嘿
Hey, um…
他去见你的朋友了
He went to go see your friend.
我试着找出这个东西的巢穴在哪
So, look, I'm trying to figure out where this thing lairs up.
能帮帮忙不
Uh, little help, maybe?
范围是什么
What are the parameters?
基本上是洞穴
Caves, basically.
但周围几英里内一个都没有
But there's nothing around for miles.
那就发散一下思维
So, less literal, then.
你那里有什么地方冰冷黑暗潮湿
What else you got local that's cold, dark, and wet?
呃
Huh.
Well, um…
这里没有地铁线路
There's no subway lines.
下水道
Sewers.
可能是这个 谢谢
That could be it. Thanks.
- 好的 - 等下 鲍比
- All right. - Wait, Bobby.
等等 你还好吧
Wait. Um… You okay?
当然 为什么这么问 怎么了
Yeah, of course. Why? What's wrong?
你言行举止有点不对劲
Besides the way you been acting and talking? Nothing.
- 你是不是有事要告诉我 - 没
- Is there something I should know? - No.
你只要知道哥斯拉躲哪就行了
All you need to know is where godzilla's holed up.
鲍比 去年发生了什么
Well, Bobby, what happened this last year?
各种的事儿
It had its moments.
和以前一样
No more than usual.
和你无关 萨姆 怎么可能和你有关
It's got nothing to do with you, sam. How could it?
当然
Right. 'course.
- 有需要就给我电话 - 嗯
- Call me if you need anything. - Ye…
卡西迪奥
Castiel, um…
我回来了
…I'm back.
如果你有时间的话
So, if you got a minute…
萨姆
Sam.
看见你活着真好
It's so good to see you alive.
是啊
Yeah.
彼此
You too.
听着 我是想抱抱你 但
Look, I-I would hug you, but …
那样挺尴尬的
That would be awkward.
多么荒唐的一年
Um… Was a crazy year, huh?
我 我刚和鲍比通过电话
I-I-I just talked to Bobby.
他把所有事都告诉我了
He … he told me everything that happened.
坦白说 你能活下来真的让我很惊讶
Frankly, I'm surprised that you survived.
我曾经求迪恩别那么做
I was begging Dean not to do it.
是啊 我明白
Yeah. No, I-I-I can understand that.
你知道吗 它没杀死你简直就是奇迹
You know, it's a miracle it didn't kill you.
是呀
Yeah.
是的 这真是个奇迹
Yeah, it's a miracle, all right.
感觉怎么样
So, how does it feel?
什么感觉
What?
当然是你找回了灵魂
Well, to have your soul back, of course.
你意思是因为之前我一直没有灵魂
Right. Y-you mean 'cause I was walking around with no soul.
很棒 小卡 我很好
Really good, Cass. I'm real good.
那个什么
You know what?
我 我在一些细节上仍然还很模糊
I'm … I'm just hazy on a few of the details, though.
也许你可以帮我回忆一下
You think maybe you could… walk me through?
等一下 我完全
Wait! I-I-I don't.
不喜欢这种做法
like this at all.
你明白吧
You do realize that this.
这可是你至今为止摸过最值钱的制品
is the single most valuable artifact you have ever touched.
这也是我们唯一的武器
It's also the only weapon we got.
听着 我知道我在做什么
Look, I know what I'm doing, okay?
事实上我都是跟鲍比学的
I actually learned it all from Bobby.
不论过去发生过什么
Hey, whatever happened there,
你清楚至少他在这方面是个天才
you know he's at least a genius at this.
你想不想让我杀掉那个龙呢
Do you want me to kill that dragon or not?
好吧
Okay.
相信我吧
Trust me.
你们些个破石头以为自己很聪明哈
You rocks think you're so smart.
差不多了
All right.
欢迎来到二十一世纪
Welcome to the 21st century.
搞定 往后站点
All right, stand back.
好了 现在
Okay. Now…
你为它买保险了吧
You've got insurance for this, right?
迪恩 我们该用它干嘛
What are we supposed to do with this, Dean?
给它一针加强剂么
Give it a booster shot?
能到手的就这个
It's what we got. All right?
我们只要靠近点儿就行了
We're just gonna have to get a little closer. That's all.
山洞找得如何了
Where are we on the caves?
不是山洞 而是下水道
Nowhere. Sewers, on the other hand…
这个 你看看
Here. Check this out.
其中两起失踪案都发生在离这一英里内
So, two of the disappearances happened within a mile of here.
所以我觉得我们从这儿开始
So I think we start there.
着手调查
and walk our way around.
棒极了 人人都爱下水道
Awesome. Who doesn't love sewers?
出发吧
Let's go.
怎么了
What?
没什么 我们走吧
Nothing. Uh, yeah, let's go.
哦 天啊
Ugh! God.
刚习惯了一种味道 又来个新的
Just when I get used to a smell, I hit a new flavor.
哥们儿 我们已经在这好几个小时了
Dude, we have been here for hours.
什么也没发现 我觉得传说不靠谱儿了
There is nothing. I think the lore is off.
如果
Hey, what if, uh…
如果龙喜欢豪华酒店呢
What if dragons like nice hotels?
- 那是什么 - 什么
- What is that? - What?
我靠
Holy crap.
好吧 也许这里真的有龙
Okay, maybe there are dragons here.
迪恩等一下
Wait. Dean…
别管那些了 看看这个
Not now. Check this out.
这大蝙蝠也太艺术范儿了吧
A little arts-and-crafty for a giant bat, right?
喂 有人吗
Hello? Is someone there?
喂
Hello?
在这里 老天啊
Over here! Oh, boys!
我们会救你们出去
Hey. We're gonna get you out.
快点 他就要回来了
Quick. He's coming back.
你准备用那个刺哪里
Where do you think you're gonna stick that?
- 你从哪拿到的 - 动漫展
- Where did you get that? - Comic-con.
快点 快点
Come on, come on.
问问我几点了 萨姆
Hey, Sam. Ask me what time it is.
你干嘛不直接躺上面打滚算了
Why don't you cut to the chase and just roll in it?
我难得有点财产
I rarely have wealth.
迪恩
Dean…
怎么了
Yeah?
我很
I am so…
很抱歉
So sorry.
我都不知如何开口
I can't even begin to say.
为什么道歉
For what?
你知道的
You know what.
- 鲍比吗 - 是小卡
- Did Bobby… - Cass.
是小卡啊 那小笨蛋
Cass. Friggin' child.
迪恩 你本该告诉我的
You should have told me, Dean.
你本来就不该知道
You weren't supposed to know.
我曾经干的好事儿
What I did?
对鲍比 对你
To Bobby? To you?
我当然应该知道
Of course I should know.
萨姆 死亡骑士并不只是
Sam, Death didn't just.
把你灵魂放回来 懂吗
shove your soul back in, okay?
他在你和你遗忘的那些事中间
He put up the great wall of Sam.
建立起了一道「萨姆之墙」
between you and the things that you don't remember.
你最好是相信我
And trust me when I say.
你不记得的那些事能杀死你
that the things you don't know could kill you.
我没在说笑
That's not a joke.
好的
All right.
但我得弥补过失 至少我要尽力而为
But I have to set things right. Or what I can, anyway.
那不是你
It wasn't you.
知道吗 我感觉
You know, I kind of feel.
就像自己喝醉了一样头脑不清
like I got slipped the worst mickey of all time…
醒过来却发现
And I woke up to find out.
我把整座城市都给烧毁了
that I had burnt the whole city down.
你可以说那不是我 但是
And you can say it wasn't me, but…
我是那个口袋里放着打火机的人
I'm the one with the zippo in my pocket, you know?
所以我不觉得事情有那么简单
So I'm not sure it's that cut and dry.
当然我很感激你是想保护我
And, look, I a-appreciate you trying to protect me.
是真的
I really do.
但我想弥补
But I got to fix…
我该补过的事
what I got to fix.
所以我得知道 我到底做了什么
So I need to know what I did.
可你不知道那有多危险
But you don't know how dangerous that could be.
换作是你呢
What would you do?
对吧 你也会这么做
Right. Same thing.
萨姆
Sam…
小伙子 你们该来看看
Boys, something I think you ought to see.
就我能得出最接近的结论
Now, as near as I can figure it,
要追溯到十四世纪
this dates back around the 14th century.
这是什么语言
What language is it?
达芬奇密码
Da vinci code.
晦涩的纯正拉丁文
Real obscure latinate.
得花上我整个黄金岁月才能翻完
Gonna take me my golden years to translate it all.
另外 友情提示 那不是纸张
Oh, and, uh, F.Y.I. … That ain't paper.
那是什么
What is it?
是人皮
It's human skin.
说正事 我已经弄明白第一部分了
Okay. I'm fairly clear on this first bit.
大意是描述了这么个地方
It basically describes this place.
就像你最可怕的噩梦的背后
It's like the backside of your worst nightmares.
充满了血腥尸骨和无尽的黑暗
It's all blood and bone and darkness.
充满了饥饿邪恶肮脏淫秽的
Filled with the bodies and souls.
尸体和灵魂
of all things hungry, sharp, and nasty.
她们人呢
Where are they?
我遇到麻烦了
I ran into trouble.
你真他妈幸运 我这里人数足够了
You're damn lucky I got enough.
今天是你的幸运日 小妞
This is your lucky day, little girl.
快点
Come on, come on.
妖怪吗
Monsters?
简直就是妖怪之地
It's monsterland.
根据这个看来 它有好多个名字
According to this, it goes by many names …
多数我都念不来
most of which I can't pronounce …
但我想你们应该知道「炼狱」
But I'm thinking you know "Purgatory."
炼狱
Purgatory?
棒极了
Awesome.
真不错
Well, that is good to know.
所以你是说 这些龙怪
So, you're saying that these, uh, dragon freaks.
蹲在下水道里
were squatting in the sewers.
拜读炼狱音诗吗
and reading tone poems about purgatory?
不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
他们读的是说明书
They're reading an instruction manual.
什么
What?
要是你疯狂到想去那种极度扭曲的地方
If you're nuts enough to want access to a place that gnarly,
这本书将告诉你如何开启这扇大门
this book will show you how to open a door.
炼狱之门
Door to purgatory.
我知道有这么个恶魔
Well, I know a demon.
他可是很乐意知道这些
who would have loved to have known about that.
那要怎样打开这扇门
So, how do you open the door?
去问那条龙吧
Ask Cloverfield.
我肯定他拿走这一页了
I'm pretty sure he's got that page.
放开我 求你们停下
Let me go! Please stop!
不
No!
- 求你们不要 - 你放松点会容易得多
- Please don't! - It'll go easier if you relax.
- 情况越来越糟 - 糟糕
- It gets worse. - Worse?
这说的可不是在那里度假之类的事
This ain't talking about how to take a vacation over there.
而是开门让什么东西进来
This is all about opening a door to let something in.
带什么东西到这里吗
Bring something here.
是什么
What?
我还在研究
I'm working on it.
能给点提示吗
Could you give us something?
- 有个名字 - 行啊
- I got a name. - Okay.
「母亲」
"Mother."
母亲 什么的母亲 龙的吗
Mother? M-mother of what? Mother of dragons?
我希望是
I wish.
这里提到过几次
It says it a few times here.
「万物之母」
"Mother of all."
恭候大驾
Welcome.
你们让我等了好久
You kept me waiting.
「万物之母」到底什么意思啊
What the hell does "Mother of all" mean?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们有很多事要做
We have so much to do.
让我们开始吧
Let's get started.